《凶鬼恶灵》  作者卡文・爱德路德
Supernatural by Carver Edlund.
我们所有的事都写在了这里
Everything is in here, I mean everything.
那辆种族歧视的卡车  我上床的细节
From the racist truck to me having sex.
-月门  -等等  那不是
- Moondoor. - Wait, is that --
维护月女王
Defend the queen of moons.
-我爱你  -我知道
- I love you. - I know.
第二道测试是什么
What's the second trial?
从地狱拯救一个无辜的灵魂
An innocent soul has to be rescued from hell
并将它送入天堂
and delivered unto heaven.
萨姆
Sam?
做完了
It's done.
凯文・谭  以为你能躲我一辈子吗
Kevin Tran. Thought you could elude me forever.
他不见了
He's gone.
小毛孩逃了
The little geek made a run for it.
如今
搞什么啊
What the hell?
这什么情况
What the hell is this?
杜鲁门否认军事试验一事
1951年
"1951"?
凶鬼恶灵
第八季 第二十集
24小时前
吃豆人热
我跟你说啊
Man, I'm telling you,
让我给你动五分钟的剪子
give me five minutes with some clippers, and --
闭嘴吧
Oh, shut up.
我什么时候睡下的
Uh, what time did I lay down?
你中午的时候睡下的
You took a siesta around noon...
昨天中午
yesterday.
抱歉
I'm sorry. Uh...
幸好我们没什么贵重东西  萨姆
That's why we don't have nice things, Sam.
你没事吧
You okay?
挺好的
Yeah, I'm -- I'm fine.
就...这样吧
Just, uh, you know what?
我去穿衣服  我们得去找凯文
I'm gonna get dressed. We should go find Kevin.
悠着点  睡美人
Easy, easy, sleeping beauty.
听我说
Look, man.
我已经黑进了盖思船屋
I've hacked into every security camera
凯文家乡  和谭太太住所周围的
around Garth's houseboat, Kevin's hometown,
所有摄像头
where mrs. Tran lived.
然后呢
And?
目前还没有动静
Well, nothing so far.
迪恩  我们得找到他
Dean, we have to find him.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
盖思出去找他了
Look, Garth is out looking for him.
我们也向其他猎人通告了凯文的事
We've got a hunter A.P.B. out on Kevin.
我们就在这儿尽力找他吧
We will do what we can from here.
等着你养好身体
While you get better.
我没事
I'm fine.
迪恩  我能出去活动
Dean, I can still go out there.
我能去猎魔
I can still hunt.
是吗
Really?
这太傻了
This is stupid.
好吧
All right.
射中靶子
You hit that target,
我们再谈让你出去行动的事
we'll talk about you getting back out there.
没问题
No problem.
第二个测试对你的伤害比第一个要大很多
Look, man, that second trial hit you a lot harder than that first one.
我不知道是因为第二个更难还是怎么的
I don't know whether it was just more intense or what.
感觉差不多
It felt the same...
但第二天就觉出不同了
Till the next day.
所以我们要按兵不动
So, we're gonna sit tight,
在这儿盯着  等你有所好转
keep an eye out until you, uh, get better.
你有新邮件
查理来的
It's from Charlie.
我就在附近  给你们找了个活儿
"In the neighborhood, found you guys a case."
找了个活儿
Found us a case?
在附近
"In the neighborhood"?
她怎么知道我们在哪
How the hell's she know where we are?
她不知道
Uh...well, she doesn't.
至少不知道准确位置
Not exactly, at least.
她说她追踪我们的手机到20英里的范围
It says she tracked our cells to a 20-mile radius,
然后信号就丢失了
then the signal went out.
这地方肯定像是百幕大三角那样的
This place must be in some kind of, like, Bermuda triangle.
你是说
What, are you saying
我们可以在这儿接听和拨打电话
that we can make and receive phone calls from here
而不被人查到吗
and nobody can track us?
我真爱这地方
Man, I love this place.
殿下
Your highness.
你们好啊
What's up, bitches?
你好吗  萨姆
You okay, Sam?
我挺好的  嗯
Yeah. No, I'm -- I'm good. Yeah.
你来堪萨斯干什么
What are you doing in Kansas?
托皮卡在举办漫展
Uh, a comic convention, in Topeka.
现在可是工作日啊
In the middle of the week?
收藏总是得去买啊
Girl's got to get her collectibles.
你们要请我去你们的地宫
So, you gonna invite me into your dungeon,
还是得先受一番审问
or do I got to answer your questions three first?
跟我们来
Follow us.
我们给你介绍记录者
Let us introduce you to the men of letters.
太帅了
Holy awesome.
可惜他们灭绝了
Too bad they got wiped out,
但是名字起的那么性感  必然要红颜薄命了
though that is what they get for the sexist name.
总之  这就是我们的秘密
Well, anyway, that's our skinny.
你呢
How about you?
跟亡灵战士做了个交易
Made a deal with the yesteryear weirdos.
我们要组团去灭了影兽人
We're gonna team up to stomp the shadow orcs.
你们还来参加年中的聚会吧
You guys are still coming to the midyear jubilee, right?
绝不错过
Wouldn't miss it.
你说的活儿呢
So, what about this case you brought us?
我在托皮卡的时候  发现了这条消息
When I was in Topeka, I saw this pop up over the wire.
萨莱纳的一个收银员  汤姆・布雷克
Tom Blake, a checkout clerk in Salina
在回家的路上失踪
who went missing on his way home from work --
昨天发现了他的尸体
He was found dead yesterday.
他的内脏
His insides?
被液化了
Liquefied.
当地警方完全摸不着头脑
Locals have no idea what happened.
他们试图把案子掩盖起来  以免引起恐慌
They tried to bury the report so people wouldn't freak,
但被我发现了
But I flagged it.
我已经排除了以下这些夜行的怪物
I have eliminated the following things that go bump in the night.
等等
Wait a second.
你什么时候变成专家了
When did you become such an expert?
你们走之后  我开始钻研各种鬼怪
Well, after you guys left, I dug into all things monstrous.
我有点点入迷
I'm a wee bit obsessive...
说一点点不如说是完全
If "a wee bit" means completely.
我还找到了卡文・爱德路德写的系列丛书
I also found this series of books by Carver Edlund.
那些书都是真的吗
Did those books really happen?
那可真是疯狂啊
That is some meta-madness.
谢谢二位拯救世界什么的
Thanks for saving the world and stuff.
很抱歉你一直得不到性福
Sorry you have zero luck with the ladies.
什么
Wha--
我们把那些书全部找到
We need to find every single copy of those books
然后烧掉
and burn them.
已经发在网上了  估计是烈火烧不尽了
They're online now, so good luck with that.
太棒了
Awesome.
你们俩疯孩子去处理那个
Well, you two crazy kids deal with that.
我去看看你找的这个活儿
I will go see if there's anything to this,
是不是真有什么
uh, case of yours.
我跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
你真的没事吗
Whoa. Are you sure you're okay?
-没事  -有事
- Yes. - No.
你没恢复之前不能出去行动
You're taking a knee as long as you're off your game.
我跟你去
I'll go with you.
无意冒犯
Look, no disrespect, okay,
但是读猎魔故事
but there is a big difference
跟真正出去猎魔的差别是很大的
between reading about hunting and actually hunting.
我去定了
I'm coming with.
真的假的
For serious?
好吧
Okay.
如果你能击中靶子
Now, if you can hit that target,
我们再说...
then we can talk about you --
怎么了
What?
如果你要跟我来
All right, if you're gonna do a ride-along, then, uh...
就把那过家家的衣服换掉
you got to lose the novelty T-shirts.
该死
Son of a pantsuit.
我的曲子
Montage.
测试  肯定不是好事
Trials? That's never good.
是啊  而且我们的先知还跑了
Yeah, and our prophet's in the wind.
卡西迪奥呢
What about, uh, Castiel?
他似乎挺有帮助  挺迷糊的
He seems helpful and dreamy.
他失踪了
He's M.I.A.,
也带着一块石碑  鬼知道他要做什么
with a tablet of his own doing god knows what.
说实话  整件事都...
I mean, to be honest, this whole thing is...
萨姆是个坚强的家伙
I mean, Sam's a tough son of a bitch,
但是小卡说这些测试对他的伤害
but Cass was saying that these trials are messing with him
连他都无法治愈
in ways that even he can't heal.
如果能给你点安慰  读了你们的历史
If it's any consolation, having read your history --
让我觉得温家兄弟合璧
there is pretty much nothing the Winchesters can't do
无所不敌
if they work together.
谢谢
Thanks.
感觉很好吧  有个弟弟
Must be nice, having a brother,
永远有人照应着你
someone to always watch your back.
是啊
Yeah.
没有兄弟姐妹吗
No brothers or sisters?
事实上  我有两个
Actually, I have two.
他们叫XBOX和PS3[都是游戏机]
Their names are xbox and ps3.
我收不到信号
I'm not getting any reception.
借你手机用用
Can I use your phone?
用吧
Mm. Sure.
-喂  -是我
- Yeah? - Hey. It's me.
你没事吧
You okay?
是的  迪恩  我依然没事
Yes, Dean, I'm still fine.
-我能去猎魔的  -那就继续养着吧
- Look, I can hunt. - Well, let the healing continue.
回头再打给你
I'll check in with you later.
够近了
Close enough.
进来
Come in.
你好  我是特别探员希克斯
Hi. Uh, special agent Hicks.
这是我搭档  特别探员雷普利
This is my partner, special agent Ripley.
我们是为内脏融化的那个尸体而来
We're here about the body with the creamy filling.
是啊
Ah, right.
没想到你们会对此有兴趣
I didn't think you guys would have any interest in that.
我们是联调局啊
FBI, ma'am.
绝不放过任何谜题
We never leave a stone unturned.
能让我们看看吗
Mind if we take a peek?
当然
Of course not.
我需要看一下签好的监管申请
I just need your signed chain-of-custody request,
尸体就归你了
and it's all yours.
抱歉  什么
I'm sorry. The what?
你上级写给我的监管申请
Chain-of-custody request from your supervisor to mine.
好吧
Right.
这样吧
Uh, you know what?
你给我上级打个电话
You want to call my supervisor?
他会同意让你移交尸体的
I'm sure he can give you the override or whatever.
抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry.
如果我拿不到申请
Unless he can get me the form,
就不能把尸体交给你
I can't give you access to the body.
但是  我们是联调局的
But...FBI.
这我知道  但是文件还是不能省
I understand, dear, but paperwork is paperwork.
当然
Of course.
詹妮弗  是詹妮弗是吧
Jennifer. Uh, it is Jennifer?
-对  -好
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我们都开车一整天了
Um, we have been on the road all day,
我知道这是正规程序
and this is strictly routine,
该查的东西都得查什么的
dot-the-"I," Cross-the-"T" kind of thing.
拜托你帮个忙了
If you could do us a solid...
带着申请表回来
Come back with the signed form.
我会很乐意帮你忙
I'd be happy to do you a solid.
在那之前
Until then...
书上可没写过这个
That never happened in the books.
你要说说刚刚怎么变成熊包了吗
You want to tell me happened back there, Boo-radley?
抱歉  我傻掉了
I'm sorry. I-I froze.
又不能退出
I couldn't control-alt-delete my way out.
现实生活中的角色扮演好难啊
Real-life role-playing is hard.
没关系
It's okay.
我们待会儿再回来
We'll come back later
等那个死板的女人下班了的
when, uh, Doris do right isn't here anymore.
太好了  还要擅闯
Oh, perfect. Breaking and entering.
跟做黑客有什么区别
No different than hacking.
我可不同意
Beg to differ.
其中一个我从少年时代就开始做了
One I've been doing since I was a teenager.
另一个我只做过一次
The other I've done once
是你们两个白痴在场外指导
with you two idiots walking me through it,
还弄断了我的胳膊
and I had my arm broken in the process.
你少年时代黑什么了
What did you hack when you were a teenager?
北美防空联合司令部
Uh...NORAD.
随便你吧  游戏狂
Yeah. Whatever you say, "WarGames."
反正得在这儿等着  去吃东西吧
Why don't we go grab some grub while we wait?
太棒了  我拿到了三颗星
Awesome. I got three stars.
那又怎样
So?
我比你高了三个级别
I'm three levels ahead of you, man.
哥们  停下
Dude, stop.
不行啊  我太厉害了
I can't. I'm just too good.
哥们
Dude!
别啊  哥们
Whoa. No, dude.
这可不太好
That's a bad idea.
你的脸才叫不太好
Your face is a bad idea.
瞧  没什么好担心的
See? Nothing to worry about.
或许这次你该先说话
Maybe you should go first this time.
继续干活儿了  孩子  快点
Back on the horse, kiddo. Come on.
你好
Hey, there.
我是特别探员雷普利
I am special agent Ripley.
这是我的搭档
This is my partner.
省省吧
Save it.
你们另一个探员在那儿呢
Your other agent's over there.
你们怎么才到
What took you guys so long?
你跑来干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
查案啊  跟你一样
Working the case. Same as you.
贾克・希尔  图书管理员
Jake Hill. Librarian.
昨天失踪  与另一个被害人无关联
Went missing yesterday, no relation to the other vic.
验尸官已经把他的遗骸收拾走了
Coroner already swooped in and scooped up what was left of him.
我们见过她了  挺死板的
Yeah. Yeah, we met her. Bit of a stickler.
这里没有尸体  没什么好看的
Well, there's, uh, not a body, nothing else to see here,
那你回家吧
so why don't you head on home?
还没跟目击者谈过呢
Still haven't talked to the witnesses.
我们来就行了
Well, we can handle that.
查理  你去跟目击者谈谈吧
Charlie, why don't you go talk to the witnesses?
我不想错过兄弟基情的戏码
But I don't want to miss the "Bro-ment."
查理
Charlie!
我知道你觉得很沮丧  但你病了
Look, man, I know you're frustrated, but you're also sick.
我不会走的  迪恩
I'm not leaving, Dean.
你们好啊
Hey, boys.
特别探员雷普利  我是联调局的
Special agent Ripley, FBI and...stuff.
你们在玩什么
What game you guys playing?
吞噬者
"Super eater."
"地下冒险"还是"异度穿越"
"Underworld adventures" or "Dimension travelers"?
"地下冒险"
"Underworld adventures."
不错啊
Nice.
你们刚刚经历的那个童年精神创伤
So, about that childhood trauma you experienced earlier.
我知道你想帮忙  我理解  但是
I know you want to help. I do, all right?But --
迪恩  你不能照顾我们两个人
Dean, you cannot take care of the both of us.
我得出来活动
I need to be out here.
这叫忍痛坚持
"Play through the pain" right?
得了  别拿我的话揶揄我
Come on, man. Don't quote me to me.
两个孩子说他们注意到胳膊上有什么东西
So, the boys said they noticed something on the body's arm
然后就被溅了一身  日后要做不少治疗了
before it covered them in years of future therapy.
说看上去像个蓝色的手印
Said it looked like a blue handprint.
看起来是你该读过的东西
Sounds like something you should read about.
在家里的某本书里
In a book. At home.
我不会走的
I'm not leaving
直到我们找到这杀人的东西
until we find out whatever's doing this.
随你吧
Whatever.
你们吵架像对老夫妻
You guys fight like an old married couple.
查理
Charlie.
这样的话我们就不用闯入验尸官的办公室了吧
Does this mean we don't have to break into the coroner's office anymore?
那是个好主意
That's a great idea.
他走了吗
Is he leaving?
他走了
He's leaving.
没事的
That's all right.
我偷了你的车  我知道他要去哪
I stole your car. I think I know where he's going.
-走吧  -好
- Come on. - Cool.
等等  你偷了我的车
Wait, you stole my car?
你怎么才到
What took you so long?
我去加油了
I stopped for gas.
闭嘴  尸体在这边
Shut up. The body's in here.
怎么回事
The hell?
查理
Charlie!
是验尸官
It's the coroner.
我来吧
I got this.
喂
Hello.
你好
Hey, there.
前门开着
Front door was open.
你来做什么
Uh, w-what are you doing here?
我来是
I, uh, came back
想要一份空白的你说的那个申请表
to get a blank copy of that form you asked for.
联调局没有监管申请表吗
The FBI doesn't have chain-of-custody forms?
外勤局电力出故障了
The field office had a power outage
因为发生了火灾
after catching fire.
我想不如来借一两份
Figured I could just borrow a copy or two.
没问题  等我一下
Of course. Just give me sec.
怎么回事
What the hell?
是空的
It's empty.
他们焚烧了尸体
They burned the bodies.
-这么快  -是
- Already? - Yeah.
他们觉得是有传染病爆发
They think it's some kind of, like, outbreak scenario.
还找了疾控中心
Even got the CDC to sign off on it.
这些人真谨慎啊
These folks run a tight ship.
好了
Okay.
给你
Here you go.
太好了
Great.
很好
Perfect.
谢谢
Thank you.
那如果没事了
Well, if you'll excuse me,
我得去停尸间工作了
I have some work to do in the morgue.
我能问个私人问题吗
Uh, can I ask you a personal question?
我还是才开始穿正装
I am new to the whole power-suit thing,
而你这套
and yours...
真是帅呆了
is killer.
你在哪买的
Where do you get them?
那我们是得赶紧给自己消毒
Does this mean we need to take "Silkwood" showers now,
还是接着查
or is this still a case?
那两个孩子说的印记我有点印象
Yeah. Something about that mark the kid saw rings a bell.
大概得去查传说
Probably have to check the lore --
或者爸爸的日记
or maybe dad's journal.
快点
Hurry up.
只需要三套短上装  三条裤子
All you need are three jackets, three pairs of pants,
就没问题了
and you're all set.
这么简单  好聪明
So simple, so smart.
你应该开个博客
You should have a blog.
好  我去整一个
Okay. I'll get right on that.
那个  还有鞋子呢
Um, so, what about shoes?
我就是找不到合适的...
I can never find the right kind to go with --
行了  抱歉  我可不是造型师
Okay. I'm sorry, but I'm not a stylist.
那么
Uh, well...
多谢你的表格和着装建议
Thanks for the forms and the fashion advice.
你最棒了
You're the best.
保持自我哦
Don't go changing.
好了  再见
'kay, bye.
利维坦
Leviathan?
他们会把猎物吞了
They consume their prey.
可能死者是利维坦
Well, maybe the vics were leviathan.
报告说两处都未见黑色胶状物
No black goo on either scene, according to the reports.
龙  它们...
Dragons. They, uh --
死者身上没有焦痕
No signs of burns on the vics.
那东西真烦人
I hate that thing.
我也想要
I want one.
等等
Wait a second.
精灵
Djinn.
被精灵整死的内脏不会融化
Djinn vics don't get liquefied.
不是  不是一般的精灵
No, no, no, no. Not regular djinn.
这里说  有一系精灵的分支
According to this, there is a bastard offshoot.
眼睛闪蓝光
Uh, their eyes light up blue.
看起来跟普通人一模一样
They pass as humans, all that regular jazz.
只不过会"让猎物的内脏变成果冻"
Except these "Leave their victims with jelly-like insides",
据称  他们给猎物下毒后
and supposedly, when they poison their victims,
会留下蓝色的掌印
they leave behind a blue handprint.
那东西真烦人
I hate that thing.
我也想要
And I want one.
那能用杀普通精灵的办法杀他们吗
So, do these things die like regular Djinn?
蘸了羔羊血的银刀  没错
Silver blade dipped in lamb's blood, yeah.
现在找到那个混蛋就行了
Now we just got to find the asshat.
好
All right.
既然有了突破  我该吃点东西了
Well, breakthrough means snack time to me.
我还想活动活动筋骨
And I want to just, uh, stretch my legs.
我会带点吃的回来
I will pick us up some grub,
萨姆  我不会像你一样  忘了馅饼
and unlike you, Sam, I will not forget the pie.
觉不觉得她有点怪
She seem a little off to you?
一来就这样
Since the second she got here.
查理
Charlie.
是我  萨姆
Hey, it's Sam.
还是那事  回电话
Uh...again, call us.
听见了吗
Okay?
查理回话了吗
Any word from Charlie?
还没
Uh, no.
托皮卡可没举办什么漫展
And there was no comic convention in Topeka.
我不知道她是为什么
I don't know why.
为什么要对我们撒谎
I mean, why would she lie to us?
有个办法查明原因
One way to find out.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我用她的手机给你打电话时
When I called you from her phone,
顺手把她的GPS打开了
I turned on her GPS.
查理
Charlie?
查理  在吗
Hey, Charlie, you in there?
迪恩
Dean.
搞什么
The hell?
这是个什么鬼地方
What the hell is this place?
不管怎样  这些都是查理的
Whatever it is, it belongs to Charlie.
或者是她的其他身份
Or some variation of her.
她是什么人  杰森・伯恩吗
Who the hell is she -- Jason Bourne?
好吧  没发现强行闯入的痕迹
All right, so, we got no forced entry,
要么是她认识的人  要么
so either it was somebody that she knew or --
精灵
Djinn.
手机上都是咱们的未接来电
Here's all our missed calls.
在电脑上发现什么了吗
You got anything on her laptop?
有
Yeah.
她在通过她的化名给托皮卡的
Uh, she's been making donations through her aliases
肖尼郡综合医院捐款
to Shawnee County General here in Topeka.
做好事吗
Like, a charity?
给一个病人  叫格特鲁德・米德尔顿
A patient. Gertrude middleton.
我们需要找到答案  我去找格特鲁德
We need answers. Uh, I'll take Gertrude.
你继续找关于精灵的事情
You keep djinn-digging.
格特鲁德16年来一直处于植物人的状态
Gertrude's been in a persistent vegetative state for 16 years.
一年前情况恶化了
About a year ago, her condition got worse.
完全靠呼吸机维持生命
This ventilator's the only thing keeping her alive.
怎么回事
How did this happen?
她和丈夫被酒驾司机撞到了
She and her husband were hit by a drunk driver.
丈夫死了
He didn't make it.
他们是去接在朋友家过夜的女儿的
They were on their way to pick up their daughter from a sleepover.
他们的女儿
Their daughter?
当时12岁
She was 12.
她父母出事后  她惹上了麻烦
She got into trouble after her parents' accident.
自那时起  没人知道她的下落
Nobody's heard from her since.
这些年大伙儿一直给格特鲁德捐医疗费
Folks have been donating to cover Gertrude's care over the years.
都是好心  但她其实已经不在了
It's a sweet gesture, but the truth is, she's gone.
有人来看望她吗
She ever get any visitors?
有几个护士曾说
A couple nurses said they thought
见到有人给她读东西
they saw someone in here reading to her,
但没人在前台签字探视
But nobody's ever officially signed in to visit her.
她一直都是孤零零的
She's all alone.
抱歉  我得去查房了
If you'll excuse me, I have to make my rounds.
谢谢
Thank you.
米德尔顿太太  你有个好女儿
You got one hell of a daughter, Mrs. Middleton.
我向你保证  我会找到她
I promise you I will find her.
别想跑
You're not going anywhere.
此处有尖叫声
Wilhelm Scream.
你知道我在你身上闻到了什么吗
Do you know what I smell on you?
止汗剂  可能还有尿
Deodorant? A little pee, maybe?
恐惧
Fear.
精灵能闻到恐惧
Djinn smell fear?
行啊
Well, well, well.
如果你们知道精灵
If you know about Djinn,
那你和你的小朋友们
then you and your little friend
就不是联调局的探员  是猎人
are hunters, not FBI.
不  我是正在打怪升级的猎人
No. I'm -- I'm more hunter-in-training.
杀我多没意思
Totally not worth killing.
杀你可有意思了  宝贝儿
Oh, but you are worth killing, sweetheart.
是啊
Yeah.
知道吗  我们这类吧...
You see, my kind --
相比一般的精灵  我们偏好苦的血
We prefer a more bitter taste to blood than the run-of-the-mill Djinn.
我们喜欢恐惧的味道
We prefer the taste of fear.
我在停尸间闻到你的味道时
And when I got a whiff of you at that morgue...
你身上散发的恐惧太诱人了
Oh, such delicious fear inside of you.
于是我跟着你的气味
I followed your scent.
我知道你足够我们两个吃了
I knew you'd make a meal fit for two.
两个
For two?
不要
No.
不会痊愈了
So, no chance of a recovery, huh?
不会
No.
不会了  格特鲁德看起来是个很棒的妈妈
No, Gertrude seemed like a cool mom, too --
和蔼  坚强  过早跟家人分离
Kind, strong, taken from her family way too young.
让你想起谁了吗
Remind you of anybody?
有发现吗
Did you find anything?
应该是
I think so.
一个九年前的无名氏
A John Doe from nine years ago.
当时的验尸官想把尸体送去疾控中心
The original coroner wanted the body sent to the CDC,
但验尸官的新助手
but the coroner's new assistant
"不小心"把尸体送去烧毁了
"accidentally" ordered the body to be burned.
-新助手  -詹妮弗・奥布莱恩
- New assistant? - Jennifer O'brien.
验尸官还真是个不错的掩护
Coroner's a hell of a cover for hiding kills.
我那个威猛的男性朋友会来抓你的
My manly man friend's gonna come get you,
你个穿职业装的怪女人
you creepy power-suit lady.
让他们尽管来
Oh, let him come.
他也害怕
He reeked of fear, as well.
看这个  疾控中心
Look at this. CDC?
这次也没收到詹妮弗的报告
Never heard from Jennifer this time, either.
她假造了报告
She faked the reports,
烧毁尸体来掩盖踪迹
burned the bodies to cover her tracks.
那怎么九年后她又变粗心了
Why'd she get sloppy again after nine years,
把尸体留在会被人发现的地方
start leaving the bodies where they could be found?
那我们去问问她
Well, let's go ask her.
根据这个
According to this,
她在镇上有两处房产
she owns two pieces of property in town --
一个离这儿十分钟的双卧室房
One 2-bedroom house about 10 minutes from here
还有一个废弃船舱
and an abandoned shipping warehouse.
当然了
Of course she does.
查理
Charlie.
Hey, Charlie.
你没事吧
You okay?
查理在哪
Where's Charlie?
怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
不知道
I don't know.
精灵不同  或许解药也不同
Uh, different djinn. Maybe she needs a different antidote.
查理
Charlie?
她在发烧  伙计
She's burning up, man.
我们不能让她化成果冻
We're not letting her turn to jello.
好的  好的
Okay, okay.
好的
Uh...okay.
精灵的毒液让人的大脑陷入循环的幻境
Djinn poison puts your brain into something like a feedback loop
同时血温开始飙升  是吧
while your blood boils, right?
是的
Right.
如果解药没能打破循环
Um, if the antidote didn't break the loop,
那我们或许应该想办法从内部打破
then maybe we can find a way to break from the inside.
精灵让你进入令你快乐的地方
I mean, djinn take you to your happy place.
那地方就像是梦境
Your happy place is like a dream.
非洲梦根
African dream root.
好吧  开始吧
All right. Let's do this.
好了  我得赶快睡着
All right, I'm gonna need to go to sleep fast,
所以...给我一拳
so, uh, punch me.
我知道你不想的  伙计
Look, man, I know you don't want to, okay?
你不大行了啊
Wow, you're a little off your game there
这太...这简直太...
'cause that was, uh, that was pretty --
如果你想活命就跟我来
Come with me if you want to live.
我一直想这么说
I've always wanted to say that.
你在我梦里做什么
What are you doing in my dream?
你被一个精灵袭击了
You were attacked by a djinn.
那个验尸官  詹妮弗  还记得吗
The coroner, Jennifer, remember?
精灵一般让你去令你开心的地方
Djinn usually send you to your, uh, happy, your happy place.
我不是说你
No judgment,
但你的欢乐点还真奇怪
but you got a really strange sense of happy, kiddo.
等等  不是的
Wait, wait, wait. No, no, no.
詹妮弗说他们汲取恐惧
Jennifer said that her kind feeds off fear.
这不是我的开心之地
This isn't my happy place.
这是我不断重复的噩梦
This is a recurring nightmare of mine.
-这是什么  -一个电子游戏
- What is this? - It's a video game.
等等
Wait a second.
你是说这一切都是个电子游戏
You're telling me that this whole thing is a video game?
叫"红色恐惧"
It was called "The Red Scare."
第一视角枪手对阵超级吸血鬼士兵
Uh, first-person shooter against super-soldier vampires.
我从一家游戏公司的服务器上拷贝了半成品
I copied it off of a game company's server before it was finished,
并重新编写  来表达我高涨的自由主义信仰
reprogrammed it to reflect my flamingly liberal politics,
然后免费发放了
and then I released it for free.
然后他们找到了我把我抓了起来
Then they tracked me down and had me arrested.
那时候我12岁
I was 12.
然后你就一直在逃
And you've been on the run ever since.
我们怎么出去
So, how do we get out of here?
不知道
I don't know.
我们给你打了精灵解药  但没用
We gave you the djinn antidote. It didn't take.
我把那精灵杀了
And I killed the djinn.
两个都杀了
Both of them?
你杀了我妈妈
You killed my mom.
我们得回去帮萨姆
We got to get back and help Sammy.
跟我说说这游戏
Tell me about this game.
如果我们能赢
Maybe if we can win --
我不知道我昏迷多久了
Look, I don't know how long I've been out,
但我已经把这关玩了一千遍了
but I've been through this level a thousand times already.
什么
What?
每次我通关救下病人
Every time I beat the level and save the patients,
我就重新回到起始
I get reset back to the beginning,
只是武器越来越少吸血鬼越来越快
only there's less weapons and the vampires are faster.
这是无限循环的
It's an infinite loop.
就像没有256关的吃豆人[电子游戏]
Like pac-man without level 256.
多少关
Level what?
没什么
Nothing.
等下  什么病人
Wait, what patients?
查理
Charlie?
我知道她是谁
I know who this is.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你失踪后
When you went missing,
我和萨姆找到了你的临时住处
me and Sam found your little crash pad.
我们看到了你给她打的钱
We saw the payments that you make for her.
我去看了你妈妈  想找你
So, I went and visited your mom, looking for you.
我是为她来到堪萨斯
She's why I'm in Kansas.
我只要可以  就会溜进医院
I sneak into the hospital whenever I can,
读书给她听
and I just -- I read to her.
我小时候  她晚上会给我读睡前故事
She used to read me to sleep at night when I was a kid.
她会读《霍比特人》给我听
She'd read me "The Hobbit."
因为她  我才会喜欢这些东西
She's the reason I love the stuff I love.
我为你失去亲人感到遗憾
I'm sorry for your loss.
她没死
She's not gone.
萨姆
Sam?
这是我的噩梦还是你的
Is this my nightmare or yours?
那么
So...
搞砸的不是你妈妈
It wasn't your mama who messed up.
是你
It was you.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我刚成年  我得吃东西
I just came of age. I had to feed.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
妈妈知道如何掩盖踪迹
M-mom knew how to cover her tracks.
她总是提醒我不要和食物玩
She always told me not to play with my food.
也许你该听你妈的话
Maybe you should have listened to your mom.
这就是最终关了
This is it -- the boss battle.
快  我们得救下病人
Come on, we got to save the patients.
等下
Wait, wait.
你说我们陷入了循环里  对吧
You said that we're stuck in a loop, right?
但在外面的真实世界里  你却快死了
And out there in the real world, you're dying.
也许我也是
And I might be, too.
我们得想办法打破这个循环
We got to find a way to break this loop.
好吧  怎么做
Okay. How?
我觉得唯一终止这事的办法就是不玩了
I think the only way to stop this is to not play.
什么
What?
不  不行  我们得救他们
No. No. We've got to save them.
快想办法  温彻斯特
Nut up, Winchester.
看  你也停不下来
See? You can't stop, either.
听我说  精灵毒液
Listen to me, this poison --
就是要让你的思维进入无限循环
It's designed to put your mind into an endless cycle
而你的内脏则开始融化  明白吗
while your insides turn to mush, okay?
它的燃料就是恐惧
And its fuel is fear.
你可以说我疯了
Now, call me crazy,
但我觉得打破循环的唯一办法
but I think the only way to break this cycle
就是不要管恐惧  不要玩游戏
is to let go of the fear and stop playing the game.
你不知道
You don't know that.
我知道是你的恐惧制造了这一切
I know that your fear is creating all of this.
但怕的不是外面那些超级吸血鬼士兵
But you're not afraid of those super-soldier vamps out there,
你怕的不是这个游戏
you're not afraid of this game,
也不是这一切对你的伤害
and you're not afraid of what it did to you.
看着我
Hey. Look at me.
你害怕失去她
You're afraid of losing her.
查理  她已经不在了
Charlie, she's already gone.
不  你不明白
No. You don't understand.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我当时在外面过夜
I was at a sleepover,
我害怕了  所以
and I got scared, so...
我打给我爸妈让他们来接我
I called my parents to come and get me.
他们那晚本不该开车出门的
They should never have been driving that night.
不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
我只想告诉她我很抱歉
I just want to tell her that I'm sorry
我爱她
and I love her
只想让她能再听到一次
and just have her hear it again.
我只需要她再听到一次
I just need her to hear that one more time.
但是她不能  她不能
But she can't. She can't.
我知道
I know.
相信我  我懂
Believe me, I know.
但是你得放手了
But you got to let her go.
游戏结束了  孩子
Game over, kiddo.
妈妈
Mom?
迪恩
Dean.
迪恩  醒醒
Dean. Hey, hey!
过来
Come here.
你没事吧  发生了什么
You okay? What happened?
-发生了什么  -我没事
- What happened? - I'm okay.
查理
Charlie?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我必须那么做
I had to.
谢谢你救了我俩的命
So, thanks for saving our bacon.
随时待命  殿下
Any time, your highness.
你知道你会没事的  对吧
You know you're gonna be okay, right?
那些书把你描绘得好像
Those books portray you as, like,
不好对付的家伙
one tough customer.
如果有谁能通过测试  那一定是你  萨姆
If anyone can get through the trials, Sam, it's you.
谢了
Thanks.
你真的应该回来
You know, you really should come back
翻看我们的档案
and dig through our archives.
你绝对是个女记录者
You are definitely a woman of letters.
听起来不错
I like the sound of that.
谢谢你顺便来访  查理
Well, thanks for stopping by, Charlie.
一直想试试进入游戏世界呢
Always wanted to get "Tron"ed.
你接下来要怎么办
What's next for you?
要去医院
Gonna go by the hospital.
得放手了  不是吗
Got to let go, right?
你呢
What about you?
你也是吗
You gonna let it go?
绝不
Never.
好样的
That's my boys.
我爱你
I love you.
我知道
I know.
好吧  你是对的
Okay, look, you were right.
我应该乖乖待着  我知道
I-I should have laid low. I-I know.
我不该过去  但我很高兴我能...
I should have hung back. But I'm glad I was able --
我们去找我们的先知吧
What do you say we find our prophet?
你想陪你妈妈多久就陪多久
Take all the time you need with your mom, okay?
最后一次  好吗
One last time, okay?
"在地底的洞府中住着一个霍比特人
"In a hole in the ground, there lived a Hobbit.
译文摘自上海人民出版社版《霍比特人》 译者  吴刚
这不是那种让人恶心的洞  脏兮兮湿乎乎的
"Not a nasty, dirty, wet hole,
长满虫子  透着一股子泥腥味儿
"filled with the ends of worms and an oozy smell,
也不是那种满是沙子的洞  干巴巴光秃秃的
"nor yet a dry, bare, sandy hole
没地方好坐  也没东西好吃
"with nothing in it to sit down on or to eat --
这是一个霍比特人的洞
"It was a hobbit-hole,
而霍比特人的洞就意味着舒适"
"and that means comfort."